<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Strolch</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Strolch</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 20:25:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strolch.li/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Release of Strolch 1.6.100</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00015/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 20:25:11 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00015/</guid><description>Release of Strolch 1.6.100 The 100. Strolch release of the 1.6 branch and a brand new website!
Ok, so Maven doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly have 100 releases on it, but even though we have been quiet on public releases, Strolch has seen many refactorings, fixes, new features etc. over the past three years of its last release.
Some notable changes:
I18n Support for StrolchExceptions. Better performance for reports on large joins.</description></item><item><title>Strolch Reports</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00014/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00014/</guid><description>Strolch Reports Strolch can do reports!
A feature we haven&amp;rsquo;t written about yet is the report API. Strolch has it&amp;rsquo;s own API to generate reports of data, and since we have a generic model, we use Resource of type Report to define them.
Go check out the documentation and then enjoy using this easy way to deliver the reports your peers require.</description></item><item><title>Strolch Searches</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00013/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00013/</guid><description>Strolch Searches Strolch queries are deprecated!
Strolch has had once again many changes, and fixes etc. One important thing to note is that we have removed support for transactional mode and have rewritten how models are searched. Thus the search API was born.
Go check out the Strolch Search documentation and then go rewrite your searches =)).
Strolch tag 1.6.51 has all those juicy changes!</description></item><item><title>Wow, the many changes!</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00012/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00012/</guid><description>Wow, the many changes! So many changes, and so long no update - not good!
Oh boy, have we forgotten to update you all on the latest awesome features in Strolch! There are over 123 commits since the last tag 1.3.0, so that alone merits a new blog post.
Currently the latest tag is 1.5.5, but this version is actually already quite old, as it was created on 31. January 2017 and there are 53 new commits ahead of the tag.</description></item><item><title>Strolch now on Maven Central</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00011/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00011/</guid><description>Strolch now on Maven Central Release Version 1.3.0 released and deployed to Maven Central
We have released a new version of Strolch so that you can now go and use the the latest features in Strolch.
Further we have now deployed Strolch to Maven Central, so it is easier than ever to use Strolch in your projects. No need to download first or use a special repository - just define the dependencies as you would any other dependency.</description></item><item><title>Versioning of objects</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00010/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00010/</guid><description>Versioning of objects Opt-In versioning of objects
A major new feature has landed in Strolch. Now, using opt-in, it is possible to have all changes to the object model be versioned. This means that any change to Order, Resource or Activity is automatically versioned and one can then revert to this version later on.
This will make it far easier to implement undo operations in applications since it is an inherent part of the lifecycle of objects in Strolch.</description></item><item><title>Release 1.2.0</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00009/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00009/</guid><description>Release 1.2.0 Release of Strolch 1.2.0
A few months ago we informed of the soon to be released version 1.1.0. Well, we decided to jump to 1.2.0 because we did some refactorings. All the eitchnet projects have been melted into Strolch and thus now it&amp;rsquo;s all one nice package. This will result in simpler development and less constraints on APIs between the two projects.
Other than that, not much changed, but we are continually working on Strolch, so go grab your latest copy and have fun coding!</description></item><item><title>Strolch Update</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00008/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00008/</guid><description>Strolch Update Long due update on Strolch development.
Although we have been rather quiet in the last couple of months, anyone viewing Strolch&amp;rsquo;s commit log, will see that we certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t halt Strolch development.
We have been hard at work, using Strolch in projects, which required many new features and fixes. The commit log shows as of today over 180 commits since the release tag 1.0.0.
Some of the most exciting changes are:</description></item><item><title>Activities: Beginning of the planning engine</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00007/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00007/</guid><description>Activities: Beginning of the planning engine The ground work of the Strolch planning engine has been laid.
One of the core ideas in building Strolch was to create a planning engine. The planning engine would work in combination of Order objects representing customer orders, Resource objects representing machines, human resources, etc., and Activity/Action hierarchies defining a workflow.
With the latest couple of commits to Strolch we have now added Activities and a basic planning of Actions onto Resources.</description></item><item><title>Strolch Documentation</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00006/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00006/</guid><description>Strolch Documentation Any good software has some decent documentation explaining concepts, best practices and gives examples.
So this post is to announce that there is now a new page on Strolch&amp;rsquo;s website with a bit of documentation. This first documentation explains the Strolch runtime and some of the do and don&amp;rsquo;t in Strolch code.
Bear with us, writing documentation takes time and can be outdated quickly, so we will make an effort to keep everything up to date and add more documentation, but this is a start.</description></item><item><title>Strolch Release 1.0.0</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00005/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00005/</guid><description>Strolch Release 1.0.0 Finally Version 1.0.0 of Strolch has been released and can be downloaded immediately.
Before 1.0.0 could be released, some major changes were decided, all driven by the first big project using Strolch as its underlying stack. Those changes were minor, and really major, but should make Strolch better and was important for the first release.
Here is a list of the most interesting changes:
Java 8 - Strolch was ported to Java 8.</description></item><item><title>DurationParameter and other minor changes: Release 1.0.0-RC4</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00004/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00004/</guid><description>DurationParameter and other minor changes: Release 1.0.0-RC4 New DurationParameter and additional minor changes: Release of 1.0.0-RC4 which can be downloaded on the download page.
While implementing a use case in a Strolch based application it was detected that an essential parameter type was missing, the DurationParameter. This parameter currently stores the value as a long in memory and serializes to ISO8601. As soon as we move Strolch to Java8, we will change this to use the Period class in the new Java8 date and time API.</description></item><item><title>DB Initialization: Release 1.0.0-RC3</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00003/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00003/</guid><description>DB Initialization: Release 1.0.0-RC3 Important feature Database Initialization added: Release of 1.0.0-RC3 which can be downloaded on the download page.
When living continuous integration and continuous delivery, it is vital that things like database migrations and initialization are performed in a controlled, but automatic way.
A Strolch-based application is using the PostgreSQL persistence layer. The implementation understands the concepts of migration, and validating the database schema, but currently a mechanism to automatically initialize the database with a minimal set of data was missing.</description></item><item><title>Release 1.0.0-RC2</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00002/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00002/</guid><description>Release 1.0.0-RC2 Scratch that RC1, here is the brand new 1.0.0-RC2 which can be downloaded on the download page.
So, as expected there were a few bugs, for instance the Strolch tutorial apps didn&amp;rsquo;t start, so now i fixed those and released an RC2. Go get it and give it a try!</description></item><item><title>Release 1.0.0-RC1</title><link>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00001/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://strolch.li/blog/post-00001/</guid><description>Release 1.0.0-RC1 With the Go-Live of a Strolch-based application around the corner, it is time to release Version 1.0.0 of Strolch. To this affect we have now released version 1.0.0-RC1 which can be downloaded on the download page.
Story Strolch as a component based software agent has been two years in the making. The concepts in Strolch have been taken from a proprietary planning, scheduling and controlling software agent, which was, and is been, used in industrial automation, logistics and production.</description></item></channel></rss>